<dashboard>
  <label>Metrics Store</label>
  <description>New data store for native support of metrics data.</description>
  <row>
    <panel> 
      <html>
      	<p><strong>Splunk now natively supports metrics!</strong></p>
      	<p>Most parts of an IT system emit metrics, from infrastructure to application performance metrics. Likewise, sensors and other devices use metrics to provide a degree of observability. Splunk now natively supports metrics as a first class data type, with a primary focus on scalability and performance.</p>
      	<p>
      	<h3>Metrics Characteristics</h3>
		<ul>
			<li>In contrast to logs, metrics are ingested as structured data in an optimized metrics index.</li>
			<li>Metrics can be used in monitoring, analysis, and investigation use cases.</li>
			<li>The main way to interact with metrics in Splunk is to run aggregation queries (such as avg, sum, or percentile) in SPL. To that end, Splunk introduces <strong>a custom search command</strong>, <code>mstats</code>. Both <code>mstats</code> and the catalog SPL command <code>mcatalog</code> are described in <a href="metrics_commands">their own page</a>.
			</li>
			<li>Because Splunk provides a single platform for logs and metrics, it's easy to correlate between the two data types, for example using <a href="event_annotations">Event Annotations</a>, or create monitoring dashboards using both logs and metrics.
			</li> 
		</ul>
      	</p>
      </html>
    </panel>
    <panel> 
      <html>
		<h3>Anatomy of a metrics index</h3>
		<table>
			<thead>
				<tr>
					<th style="text-align:left">Field</th>
					<th style="text-align:left">Required</th>
					<th style="text-align:left">Description</th>
					<th style="text-align:left">Example</th>
				</tr>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<tr>
					<td>metric_name</td>
					<td>Yes</td>
					<td>The metric name.</td>
					<td>os.cpu.user</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>_time</td>
					<td>Yes</td>
					<td>The timestamp of the metric in UNIX time notation.</td>
					<td></td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>_value</td>
					<td>Yes</td>
					<td>The numeric value of the metric.</td>
					<td>41.1234</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>&lt;dimension A&gt;...&lt;dimension Z&gt;</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>An arbitrary number of dimensions, each as a separate field.</td>
					<td><strong>Field:</strong> ip; <strong>Value:</strong> 10.2.1.166</td>
				</tr>
			</tbody>
		</table>
		<p>Apart from these fields, each event is also assigned host, source, sourcetype, and index, just like with Events based indexes.</p> 
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

</dashboard>